ILGWU Local 23-25 Publications 5780/059 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 23-25 Publications
1959-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Local 23-25
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/059 PUBS
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications.
Consists primarily of issues of Local 23- 25's publication, Local 23-25 News, from 1970 to 1995. Also included are other publications of the local, including its annual reports from 1971 to 1979.
6766093
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 11, 2010
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 10, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Local 23-25 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers' Union, was based in New York, New York.
Scope and Contents
The collection contaians issues of Local 23-25's publication, Local 23-25 News, from 1970 to 1995. Also included are other publications of the local, including its annual reports from 1971 to 1979.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/059 P: ILGWU Local 23-25 Photographs 5780/059: ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/095: ILGWU Local 23-25 Records 5780/095 G: ILGWU Local 23-25 graphics 5780/042: ILGWU Local 25 Publication "L'Operaia" 5780/139 mf: ILGWU Local 25 Publication "L'Operaia" on Microfilm 5780/071: ILGWU Local 25 Publication "The Message"
Textile workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 23-25 (New York, N.Y.); Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees. Local 23-25 (New York, N.Y.); UNITE HERE (Organization)
6766093
- Local 23-25 News, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  English and Spanish. February, May, June, October
- Local 23-25 News, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Chinese. July. Two different issues for same month.
- Local 23-25 News, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  English and Spanish. March, June, October
- Local 23-25 News, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  English and Spanish. January, May, October
- Local 23-25 News, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Chinese. November.
- Local 23-25 News, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  English and Spanish. March, April, June, November.
- Local 23-25 News, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Local 23-25 News, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  January, March, May, October, December
- Local 23-25 News, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Chinese. May, November
- Local 23-25 News, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  English and Spanish. March, May, October
- Local 23-25 News, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Chinese. June, December
- Local 23-25 News, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  English and Spanish. January, April, June, October
- Local 23-25 News, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Chinese. May, July, October
- Local 23-25 News, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  English and Spanish. January, March, May, July, November
- Local 23-25 News, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Chinese. January, May, July, December
- Local 23-25 News, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  English and Spanish. February, May, June, September, November
- Local 23-25 News, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Chinese. March, June, December
- Local 23-25 News, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  English and Spanish. January, April, June, September, November
- Local 23-25 News, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Chinese. February, May, July, October, December
- Local 23-25 News, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  English and Spanish. February, March, June, September, November/December
- Local 23-25 News, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Chinese. February, March, June, October, November/December
- Local 23-25 News, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  English and Spanish. February, June
- Local 23-25 News, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Chinese. March
- Local 23-25 News, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Korean. March
- Local 23-25... More Than A Union, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  English and Spanish. Report of Gains Made
- Justice, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  v.53:no.9 (1971:May 1).
- Local 23-25... More Than A Union, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Chinese. Report of Gains Made
- Report, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- On the Move, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Years of Progress, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Report, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Local 23-25 News, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  English. V.30:no.4 (1981:Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Chinese. v.30:no.4 (1981:Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  English. v.30:no.5 (1981:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Chinese. v.30:no.5 (1981:Oct.)1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  English v.30:no.6 (1981:Dec.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  English v.31:no.1 (1982:Feb.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  English v.31:no.2 (1982:Apr.)1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  English v.31:no.3 (1982:Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Chinese. v.31:no.3 (1982:Aug.)3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Korean. v.31:no.3 (1982:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  English. v.31:no.4 (1982:Nov.) 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  English v.32:no.1(1983:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  English v.32:no.2(1983:Mar.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Chinese. v.32:no.2 (1983:Mar.)1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  English v.32:no.3 (1983:May) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Chinese. v.32:no.3 (1983:May)1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  English v.32:no.4 (1983:July/Aug.) 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Chinese. v.32:no.4 (1983:July/Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  English. V.32:no.5 (1983:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  English. V.33:no.1 (1984:June/July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Chinese. v.33:no.1 (1984:June/July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  English v.33:no.2 (1984:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Chinese. v.33:no.2 (1984:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Chinese and English. V.33:no.3 (1984:Dec.) 3c
- Local 23-25 Calendar, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  English, Chinese, and Spanish.3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  English v.34:no.1 (1985:May) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Chinese. v.34:no.1 (1985:May) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  English. v.34:no.2 (1985:Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Chinese. v.34:no.2 (1985:Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  English v.34:no.3 (1985:Nov.) 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Chinese. v.34:no.3 (1985:Nov.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  English v.35:no.1 (1986:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Chinese. v.35:no.1 (1986:Jan.) 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  English v.35:no.2 (1986:May) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  English v.35:no.3 (1986:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  October v.35:no.3 Chinese. v.35:no.3 (1986:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  English v.36:no.1 (1987:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Chinese. v.36:no.1 (1987:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  English v.36:no.2 (1987:Apr.) 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Chinese. v.36:no.2 (1987:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  English and Spanish. v.36:no.3 (1987:July) English 3c Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  July v.36:no.3 Chinese. v.36:no.3 (1987:July)3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Englishv.36:no.4 (1987:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Chinese. v.36:no.4 (1987:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  English and Spanish. v.37:no.1 (1988:Jan.) Spanish 1c, English 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Chinese. v.37:no.1 (1988:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  English and Spanish. v.37:no.2 (1988:Mar.) 1c each
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Chinese. v.37:no.2 (1988:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  English. v.37:no.3 (1988:May) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Chinese. v.37:no.3 (1988:May) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  English v.37:no.4 (1988:Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Chinese. v.37:no.4 (1988:Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  English and Spanish. v.37:no.5 (1988:Oct.) English 3c, Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Chinese. v.37:no.5 (1988:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  English and Spanish. v.38:no.1 (1989:Feb.) English 2c, Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Chinese. v.38:no.1 (1989:Feb.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  English and Spanish. v.38:no.2 (1989:Apr.) English 3c, Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Chinese. v.38:no.2 (1989:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  English and Spanish. v.38:no.3 (1989:July)English 3c, Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Chinese. v.38:no.3 (1989:July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  English. v.38:no.4 (1989:Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Chinese. v.38:no.4 (1989:Aug.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  English and Spanish. v.38:no.5 (1989:Oct.)Spanish 2c, English 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Chinese. v.38:no.5 (1989:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  English. v.39:no.1 (1990:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Chinese. v.39:no.1 (1990:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  English v.39:no.2 (1990:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Chinese. v.39:no.2 (1990:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  English and Spanish. v.39:no.3 (1990:July) English 3c; Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Chinese. v.39:no.3 (1990:July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  English v.39:no.4 (1990:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  Chinese. v.39:no.4 (1990:Oct.) 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  English and Spanish. v.40:no.1 (1991:Jan.) English 3c; Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  Chinese. v.40:no.1 (1991:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  Englishv.40:no.2 (1991:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  Chinese. v.40:no.2 (1991:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  English and Spanish. v.40:no.3 (1991:July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  Chinese. v.40:no.3 (1991:July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  English and Spanish. v.40:no.4 (1991:Oct.) English 3c, Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  Chinese. v.40:no.4 (1991:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  English and Spanish. v.41:no.1 (1992:Jan.) English 3c, Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  Chinese. v.41:no.1 (1992:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  English and Spanish. v.41:no.2 (1992:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  Chinese. v.41:no.2 (1992:Mar) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  English and Spanish. v.41:no.3 (1992:July) English 3c, Spanish 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  Chinese. v.41:no.3 (1992:July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  English and Spanish. v.41:no.4 (1992:Oct.) English 3c, Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  Chinese. v.41:no.4 (1992:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  English and Spanish. v.42:no.1 (1993:Jan.) Spanish 2c; English 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  Chinese. v.42:no.1 (1993:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  English and Spanish. v.42:no.2 (1993:Apr.) Spanish 3c; English 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  Chinese. v.42:no.2 (1993:Apr.)3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  English v.42:no.3 (1993:July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  Chinese. v.42:no.3 (1993:July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  English and Spanish. v.42:no.4 (1993:Oct.) Spanish 3c; English 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  Chinese. v.42:no.4 (1993:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  English v.43:no.1 (1994:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  Chinese. v.43:no.1 (1994:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  English v.43:no.2 (1994:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  Chinese. v.43:no.2 (1994:Apr.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  English v.43:no.3 (1994:July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  Chinese. v.43:no.3 (1994:July) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  English v.43:no.4 (1994:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  Chinese. v.43:no.4 (1994:Oct.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  English and Spanish. v.44:no.1 (1995:Jan.) Spanish 3c; English 2c
- Local 23-25 News, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  Chinese. v.44:no.1 (1995:Jan.) 3c
- Local 23-25 News, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  English and Spanish. v.44:no.2 (1995:Apr.) English 3c; Spanish 1c
- Local 23-25 News, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  Chinese. v.44:no.2 (1995:July: 3c) (1995:April:1c)
- Local 23-25 News, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  English v.44:no.3 (1995:July) 3c
- Labor Against Apartheid, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  Fall 1990 3c
- Labor Against Apartheid, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  Winter1992 3c
- Rainbows: ILGWU Local 23-25 Worker-Family Education Program, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  English and Chinese. 2 Volumes
- Local 23 News, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 82)